hi yes its copyright dispute time again
on YouTube and this has been going on
since well day dot really copyright
claims on YouTube videos and it used to
be that the YouTube automated algorithm
many years back would like falsely
identify just or even regular speech and
the algorithm wasn't that good and there
was a spate of you know if false
copyright ID claims for content
producers like me but you just disputed
it and went away no problems whatsoever
if you'll follow me on Twitter just a
couple of days back I got a copyright ID
claim for one of my arm older videos and
I thought ok well they've matched it
somehow it like you know it's just a
false match and I'll dispute it sure
enough I disputed it and they said yep
ok no worries we drop our claim and
everything was hunky-dory but then I got
another one and I disputed that that was
on my Chronos high-speed camera view
here and then I got the email back
saying the dispute was not approved ie
copyright claimant was going nope we
have reviewed this manually and we own
the rights to it in in in it we're going
to demilitarize your video and take all
future revenue on all views of that
video from you here's the email that you
get after reviewing your dispute ad Rev
for rights holders this is the company
which we'll take a look at has decided
that their copyright claim is still
valid they're the ones who get to make
the decision video title Chronos
high-speed camera view the copyrighted
content is clear vision which we'll get
into that is actually correct so they
have I did the correct thing and claimed
to buy a drive for rights holders view
claim details blah blah blah your
copyright owner might disagree with me
the reason gave for disputing the claim
may have insufficient or invalid they're
just basically saying bugger off no we
own the rights well this morning I got
another there's only four here but I've
got another five emails so seven total
of five different videos seven different
videos that have been flagged by this
same
rev for rightsholders for basically the
same content a copyright owner using
Content ID claims some material on your
video don't worry you're not in trouble
and your account standing is not
affected by this yet we'll get into that
there are either ads running on your
video if the revenue going to cooperate
I know the copyright owner is receiving
stats about your video views your video
was manually reviewed on behalf of the
copyright owner so it's been manually
reviewed by the copyright owner or on
behalf of the copyright owner and once
again it is found wild chase fugitive
and that is correct which I'll show you
in a minute
once again ad Rev for rights holders now
you can go in here as a content
producing here's one that they've
claimed ads might appear in your videos
copyrighted content was found the
claimant is allowing their content to be
used off thank you so generous I'm not
worthy
however ads might appear on it and they
get the money from any future views
until I dispute it and win the dispute
so wild chase now where this is coming
from a lot of my videos anything that
includes time lapse things I typically
put in a soundtrack in the back of it
just to you know keep people interested
while they're watching a time-lapse I've
done a few videos like that I don't
normally have audio in my videos but I
get that from a program called our sonic
Fire Pro which I have purchased and I
owned the rights to it's a royalty-free
music thing and here it is wild chase
down here and clear vision these are the
two that I typically use in my videos
and you might I don't want to go this
video might get flagged but so let's
play a quick thing to do it and clear
vision sounds like and you can do all
sorts of things you can change the
variation of it you can change the mood
whether or not it's more background D
and stuff like that you can sort of mix
it yourself kind of thing it's quite
cool it's a company called smart sound I
purchased this software a couple of
years back if we go down and have a look
at the
license comparison chart it says
monetized videos on YouTube Vimeo
Facebook etc the extend both versions of
the license cover that I am fully
covered I paid for this software I am
the rights holder I have a license to
use this and that's what I wrote in my
dispute claim for one of them my first
video and they accepted that the second
one I wrote the same thing and they
didn't accept it so I've got another
five videos that I have to dispute for
this now who are ad Rev for rights
holders you might think there's some
copyright troll um I don't think that
they are because what they do if you go
into the website and have a look and
they call themselves ad Rev for rights
holder so ad Rev are not the company who
is claiming the rights to this copyright
falsely claiming the rights to this
copyrighted content it's actually they
act on behalf of the rights holder so
they're like a service company you know
are you an independent musician label or
publisher our self-service system allows
you to easily protect and monetize your
content and your copyrighted content on
YouTube so ad Rev have a deal with
YouTube where they can upload supposed
copyright material it goes into the
YouTube see id algorithm with the
Content ID algorithm and like little
snippets of it and then I believe it's a
if it's longer than 20 seconds it
usually gets our flag anything under 20
seconds it usually doesn't get flagged
that's a bit of a rule of thumb on
YouTube but may or may not be correct
it's probably changing all the time
they're not claiming the rights but
they're acting on behalf of somebody who
doesn't tell you there is no
transparency in these emails whose the
rights holder who's actually making this
claim you can't actually get this detail
so I have no idea who's actually making
this claim I mean smartsound they
shouldn't be making the claim because
they that's their business model they
sell software to produce royalty free
music for channel 4 platforms like
YouTube so I don't think
salmon's but it has the same name wild
chase and clear vision so they someone
somewhere has claiming rights to this
even though I fully own and have a
license for it now the other thing is
check this out okay this is the one that
I disputed and it was my dispute was
rejected on the Khronos high-speed
camera one the claimant has reviewed bla
bla bla bla bla you may be able to
appeal this decision here it is appear
or reject a dispute down here but if the
claimant disagrees if they disagree and
of course they're going to disagree
right because they've already reviewed
it manually before with your appeal you
could end up with a strike on my channel
now if you're not aware youtubers if you
get three strikes on your channel right
if it's copyright claims if it's abuse
or whatever it is your channel gets shut
down there's no recourse
it just gets shut down they lock you out
you can't do anything you're out of the
youtube business like five other videos
I have to dispute you know if they
reject the dispute and then I can appeal
but if I appeal all three of them and
lose the appeal my channel is shut down
they're like holding the gun to my head
it's like they're relying on the fact
that YouTube is going to be so scared to
do this to actually appeal this dispute
that it's not going to work and I
believe you've only got a time limit to
do it as well so that I can't just leave
it like do maybe one appeal because your
strikes disappear after a certain amount
of time like a month or something I
believe I've never had a strike on my
channel I don't think but yeah they
disappear after certain time if you only
got a certain time to appeal all these
things so I believe anyway it's just
nuts and here we go we can actually play
the matched content in here so dude
that's the clear vision song like there
it is right I've got it in the
background there and so it matches so
it's not like a just a mismatched
algorithm thing somebody is claiming
rights to this smartsound stuff on the
smarts
system so smart sound should be really
pissed about this because they their
business models selling this software to
youtubers like me who can produce this
sort of music anyway it's just nuts
it's just absolutely nuts and they rely
on the fact that they can just upload so
much content in this Content ID system
it could affect thousands tens of
thousands of youtubers or whatever
depending on what the content is they're
relying on the fact that people aren't
gonna sue them right they're just not
going to go to the effort they're just
going to have to take it up the ass and
I go well okay I lose all you know
future revenue on those videos anyway so
they're they're basically this ad Rev
for rights holders they're a service
company but they're basically
anonymizing copyright trolls because I
have no idea I have no clue who the
rights holder actually is so it's just
like unbelievable I I could contact
every ad Rev maybe and try and figure
this out or try and sort it out but like
it's just ridiculous so I and I've got
probably a lot of videos with that time
lapse are stuff in it so I probably
expect a few more claims to come through
but obviously I'm gonna have to stop
using that I'm gonna have to find some
other background music but then that
could get flagged by somebody else and
it's just it's a ridiculous situation
that youtubers are put in like this oh
we got a gun to our head you appeal this
three times you're out of business if
you lose you lose the appeal you can end
up with strikes on your counter it's
just unbelievable so there's basically a
penalty for content producers like me it
could be a channel ending penalty if you
get three strikes on your account for
appealing these disputes that you might
lose but there's basically no downside
for these companies because there's no
recourse there's nothing I can do they
don't get a three strikes system for you
know incorrectly flagging things or
something like that you know why can't
there be some sort of system like that
that if they get more than I know
they're a big
with lots of claims in everything and
they represent lots of content producers
but like if they basically get you know
X amount of false claims per day or
something then they should you lose
their license for this Content ID system
because obviously it's causing too much
issues for content producers they're
basically abusing the systems but
there's no recourse to that there's no
penalty for these companies at all so
I'm going to go through now and dispute
these five new claims and see what
happens I'll keep you updated in the
comment and comments and down below and
also on Twitter and stuff like that so
follow along to see I'm not going to
appeal any of them well maybe I can do
one and then take a strike on my channel
you know take one for the team maybe I
don't know but anyway keep following
along down below absolute so
yeah ad Rev unbel it like who knows how
many copyright like clients they've got
uploading all this copyright content but
it's just anyway there you go
that's just a little rant of what us
youtubers have to put up with something
that I own the rights to and I try and
prove it to them and they go no sorry we
have to sit we've deemed that we still
own the rights tough titties take it up
the ass thanks anyway
if this has happening to you you know of
other channels that have been hit by you
know this ad Rev mob on behalf of some
anonymous it could be some anonymous
copyright troll we don't know
unbelievable anyway if you know of other
channels hit with the same thing I think
I'm in down below discuss down below
catch you next time